她将生下我的小孩,她却还没来
She's having my baby,and she's not here yet.
-她的羊水破了吗? -我不知道
-Has her water broken yet? -I don't know.
她和我通话时说她已分泌粘液
When we talked,she said she'd already passed the mucous plug.
我们需要知道这一些吗?
Do we have to know about that?
乔伊,你有小孩时你会怎么做?
What'll you do when you have a baby?
我会在等待室中送雪茄
I'll be in the waiting room,handing out cigars.
乔伊准备让他孩子出生在50年代的电影中
Joey's made arrangements to have his baby in a movie from the '50s.
我不敢相信她可能会在计程车中生产
She could be giving birth in the cab.
罗斯,冷静点第一次收缩收费二块钱
Relax. It's only $2 for the first contraction...
之后每收缩一次收五毛钱
...and then 50 cents for each additional contraction.
怎么了?钱德这样说时就没事
What,it's okay when Chandler does it?
你得选对时间
You have to pick your moments.
我错过了吗?
Did I miss it?
-没有,她根本还没出现 -干嘛带吉他来?
-She's not here yet. -What's with the guitar?
我想我们会在这儿待一阵子,来点音乐
We might be here for a while. Things might get musical.
-你到底上哪儿去了? -我们中途在礼品店待了一会儿
-Where have you been? -We stopped at the gift shop.
我想买这个,苏珊想买“矮胖”
I got this,and Susan wanted a Chunky.
我们就快要有孩子了，你不能为了“矮胖”而停下
（此句像汽车贴纸上说的俏皮话）
You're having a baby. You don't stop for Chunkies.
我过去也用那个汽车贴纸
I used to have that bumper sticker.
懂我意思吗?
You see what I mean?
六人行 第1季 第23集 生孩子
The One With the Birth
-下车买矮胖 -别介意了,罗斯
-"Stopped for a Chunky." -Let it go,Ross.
我多了一个,想要吗?不想
I got an extra one. You want this?
-我最喜爱的父母团队好 -法大夫
-How's my favorite parenting team? -Dr. Franzblau.
我了解你们在考虑生宝宝的事
I understand you're thinking of having a baby.
我知道你已怀胎九月 这是好的开始
I see you're nine months pregnant. That's a good start.
-收缩的情况如何? -我喜欢
-How are your contractions? -I love them.
每一阵都像是子宫中的小舞会
Each one's like a little party in my uterus.
-每4分钟,持续55秒 -59秒,石英表
-Every 4 minutes,lasting 55 seconds. -59 seconds. Quartz.
瑞士石英表
Swiss quartz.
-我能喝饮料吗? -碎冰
-Am I allowed to drink anything? -lce chips.
-护士站有 -我去拿
-At the nurse's station. -I'll get it!
-不,我去,马上回来 -不,我去…
-No,I'll get it. -No,I'm getting it.
我想你或许想喝碎冰
Hi. Thought you might like some ice chips.
-谢谢. -如果还需要别的…
-Thanks. -And if you need anything else l...
我们没见过吧?
...do not believe we've met.
我叫瑞秋格林
I'm Rachel Greene.
卡萝前任丈夫妹妹的室友
I'm Carol's ex-husband's sister's roommate.
幸会,我是法大夫
Nice to meet you. I'm Dr. Franzblau.
你室友哥哥前妻的医生
I'm your roommate's brother's ex-wife's obstetrician.
真有趣
Oh,that's funny.
我想要个宝宝
I want a baby.
今晚不行,亲爱的我明天得早起
Not tonight,honey. I got an early day tomorrow.
-起来,我们去买咖啡 -好吧,因为我们没做过
-Get up. Let's get some coffee. -Okay,because we never do that.
投.投.投.或是不进也行
Shoot,shoot,shoot. Or just fall down. That's good too.
尼克斯迷?
Knick fan?
-他们烂透了 -听着,女士
-Oh,boy,do they suck. -Listen,lady
看,你的尤恩
Look. Look at your man,Ewing.
他连坐在船上都投不进水里
He couldn't hit water if he was standing on a boat.
-是吗?你支持谁? -凯尔特人
-And who do you like? -Celtics.
凯尔特人?他们不可能击中船的，除非
Celtics? They couldn't hit a boat if
等等
Wait....
反正他们很烂
They suck,all right?
闭嘴,今年是重建年
Shut up. It's a rebuilding year
我帮你叫孩子的爸爸,我们这儿需要爸爸…
Let me get the father. We need a father over here.
这里没有爸爸
There's no father.
-抱歉 -没关系,我没事
-Oh,sorry. -That's okay. I'm fine.
这边来
Okay. Right this way.
所有的孕妇似乎都往这儿走
All the other pregnant women seem to be going in here.
他们又小又肉摸起来感觉很好
They're tiny and chubby And so sweet to touch
不久他们长大后就会开始恨你
But soon they'll grow up And resent you so much
现在他们对你大吼大叫,你不知原因为何
Now they're yelling at you And you don 't know why
你只能哭啊,哭啊,你哭啊
And you cry and you cry And you cry
-谢谢,罗斯 -用来叫你停止的好吧
-Thanks,Ross. -I'm paying you to stop.
看,是双胞胎,好可爱
Oh,look,twins. Hi,guys. Oh,cute.
不公平
No fair.
我一个都没有,他们怎会有两个?
I don't even have one. How come they get two?
-你也会有的 -什么时候?
-You'll get one. -When?
好吧,告诉你.我们40岁时如果都还单身
Tell you what. When we're 40,if neither of us are married...
我们就一起生一个,如何?
...what do you say we have one?
为何我40岁时还单身?
Why won't I be married when I'm 40?
不,这只是假设
I just meant hypothetically.
假设为何我到40岁时还单身?
Hypothetically,why won't I be married when I'm 40?
为什么?我有不适婚姻的毛病吗?
What is it? Is there something unmarriable about me?
好吧?
Well?
亲爱的上帝!这降落伞是个背包
Dear God! This parachute is a knapsack.
看你,盛装登场
Look at you,dressy-dress.
你回家换衣服?
Did you go home and change?
今天是个重要的日子,我想漂亮一点
It's an important day. I want to look nice.
法大夫来了吗?
Has Dr. Franzblau been by?
不,我们还没见到他
I haven't seen him.
他在哪儿?他应该在这儿的
Where is he? He is supposed to be here.
万一小孩需要他怎么办?
What if the baby needs him?
瑞秋,你和医生到底是怎么了 难道你爸也是个医生?
What's the deal with you and doctors? Is your father a doctor?
对,干嘛问?
Yeah. Why?
没理由
No reason.
妈妈,我们能过去的
Mom,we've been through this.
不,我不找他
No,I am not calling him.
我不管这是不是他的孩子,他是个大浑蛋
I don't care if it is his kid,the guy's a jerk.
不,我不是一个人,乔伊在这儿
No,I am not alone. Joey's here.
什么意思?乔伊什么?
What do you mean "Joey who"?
乔伊什么?
Joey who?
-崔比亚尼 -乔伊崔比亚尼
-Tribbiani. -Joey Tribbiani.
对,等等
Yes. Okay. Hold on.
她要跟你谈
She wants to talk to you.
拿着电话
Take the phone.
对,是我
Yeah,it's me.
不,我们只是朋友
No,we're just friends.
对,我单身
Yeah,I'm single.
25岁
Twenty-five.
演员
An actor. Hello?
她不善于讲电话
She's not much of a phone person.
孩子的爸怎么了?
So,what's the deal with this father guy?
如果有人即将生下我的孩子,我会想知道的
If someone was having my baby,I'd wanna know about it.
尼克斯迷,你对爸爸的观点我不在乎
Hey,Knick fan,am I interested in your views on fatherhood? No.
-或许吧我应该走了. -也许应该
-Maybe I should just go. -Maybe you should.
祝你好运
Good luck...
保重了
...and take care.
你知道凯尔特人有什么问题? 他们让球员经营球队
The Celtics problem is that the players run the team.
-这不是真的 -这当然是真的
-That is so not true. -Oh,it is.
-深呼吸 -深呼吸
-Breathe. -Breathe.
你们会害死我的
You're gonna kill me.
-剩15秒 -14,13,12数快点
-Fifteen more seconds. 1 4,1 3,1 2 -Count faster.
你会没事,记得这样做全是为了裘帝,他马上就到了
It'll be okay. IKeep focusing on Jordy. He'll be here soon.
-3,2,1.裘帝到底是谁? -你儿子
-Three. Two. Who the hell is Jordy? -Your son.
不,我不要我儿子叫裘帝,我们协议过,我儿子叫洁米
I don't have a son named Jordy. We all agreed on Jamie.
洁米是苏珊第一任女友的名字
Jamie was the name of Susan's first girlfriend...
所以我们决定还是用裘帝
...so we went back to Jordy.
这是什么意思?还是用裘帝,我们根本没讨论过裘帝
What do you mean,back to Jordy? We never landed on Jordy.
我们讨论过杰西科德迪伦时提到一下
We just passed by it during the whole Jesse-Cody-Dillon fiasco.
我脚抽筋
Ow! Leg cramp!
-我明白了 -明白,我来处理
-I got it. -I got it. I'm doing it.
你和她睡觉,我来处理抽筋
You get to sleep with her. I get the cramps.
你不行
No,you don't.
够了,你们都给我出去
That is it. I want both of you out.
-什么?是她引起的… -他…
-She started it. -He did.
我不管,我想生下小孩
I'm trying to get a person out of my body here...
你们在这儿根本是愈帮愈忙
...and you're not making it any easier! Now go!
-谢谢 -看你干了什么?
-Thanks. -See what you did?
-听着 -出去!
-Listen -Out!
深呼吸.深呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
怎么了?有东西爆炸了
What is that? Something exploded.
-不是婴儿 -她的羊水破了,冷静点
-That's not the baby,is it? -Her water broke. Calm down.
羊水破了?你什么意思?
Water breaking? What do you mean? What's that?
深呼吸.深呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
我很好,我很好,这样真讨厌,我很好
I'm okay. I'm okay. That's disgusting. I'm okay.
-这都是你的错 -为什么都是我的错?
-This is so your fault. -How is this my fault?
你们在一起之前卡萝从未把我赶出房间
Carol never threw me out of a room before you.
我出现之前有许多事卡萝没做过
There's a lot of things Carol never did before me.
-知道你的问题出在哪儿吗? -你因我而感到岌岌可危
-Are you trying to be clever? -You're so threatened by me.
嘿,好吧,就这样,进去
Hey. Okay,all right. That's it. Get in here.
天哪,伙计们,我简直不敢相信你们两个
My God,you guys. I don't believe you.
小宝宝即将诞生在这栋建筑
There are children coming into the world here...
他听见的第一个声音不该是你们的吵闹声
...and your fighting isn't the first thing they should hear.
所以你们别再吵了
So stop all the yelling! Just stop it!
别让我再发一次脾气 我不喜欢我自己这样
Don't make me do this again! I don't like my voice like this!
谁想听讽刺的事?
Who wants to hear something ironic?
他们到了吗?
Are they here yet?
不要担心,我们会找到他们的
Don't worry,we're gonna find them.
找到之前,我们都会在这儿陪你的
And until we do,we are all here for you. Okay?
你告诉我巴黎的事真棒
You were telling me about Paris. It sounds wonderful.
那家糕饼店就在我住的饭店隔壁
There was this great little pastry shop right by my hotel
加油,加油,亲爱的
There you go,dear.
-你找到他们啦? -不是在礼品店或者咖啡厅
-You find them? -Not in the gift shop or cafeteria....
菲比和乔伊在哪里?
Where are Phoebe and Joey?
我想这里有点险恶
There's something sinister going on here.
如果你找到任何人,或者任何人的一部分
If you find anyone,or parts of anyone...
就大叫,不停的大叫
...scream. And scream again.
-救命! -拜托
-Help! -Come on!
-我的孩子就要出世了! -嗨
-I'm having a baby in there! -Hello!
大家退后
Okay,everyone stand back.
噢
Ow.
好吧,幸好我们在医院里
All right,good thing we're in a hospital.
加油,莉迪亚,你办得到
Come on,Lydia,you can do it.
用力,用力,使劲,使劲
Push him out,push him out. Harder,harder.
用力,用力,推他出来
Push him out,push him out. Way out.
我们抢球而且真的动了
Let's get that ball and really move.
我们…
Let's get
我只是,好吧,用力,用力,用力
I was just Yeah,okay. Push,push,push.
你想干嘛?将门吸开?
What are you gonna do,suck the door open?
救命!救命!
Help! Help!
第二天,他们终于发现他们的尸体
And they found their bodies The very next day
他们终于发现他们的尸体
And they found their bodies The very next
妈妈,一切顺利
Mom,everything's going fine.
对,罗斯很好
Ross is great.
他在其他地方
He's in a whole other place.
不,他不见了
No,he's gone.
不,你们不用飞回来.真的
No,you don't have to fly back. Really.
什么叫可能是你们唯一的机会?我才26岁
What do you mean "This might be your only chance"? I'm only 26.
我连小孩的事都没想过
I'm not even thinking about babies yet.
-你上哪儿去了? -我刚生了个小孩
-Where have you been? -I just had a baby.
好运气（希伯来语）
Mazel tov.
说不定,或许是一小时也可能是三小时
It could be one hour or three.
但请放心,她的状况良好
But relax. She's doing great.
告诉我,你目前有对象吗?
So tell me,are you currently involved with anyone?
没有,现在没有,你呢?
Not at the moment,I'm not. Are you?
没有,我不容易找到对象
No,it's hard enough to get women to go out with me.
对,我听过有关帅哥大夫不好找对象的传闻
Right. Yeah,I've heard that about cute doctors.
没有,真的.我想这是因为我花了太多的时间
No,really. I suppose it's because I spend so much time,you know...
在我所工作的那个东西上
...where I do.
我试着不让工作影响我的生活
I try not to let work affect my personal life.
当你做我所做的事情的时候很难,就像…
But it's hard when,when you do what I do. It's,like....
等等,举个例子，你从事什么工作?
Well,for instance,what do you do?
我是服务生
I'm a waitress.
难道你下班回家后不会觉得…
Aren't there times when you come home at night and you're,like:
如果我再看见咖啡杯…
"If I see one more cup of coffee...."
我懂
Gotcha.
-我去看看你朋友. -很好
-I'm gonna check up on your friend. -That's fine.
-你怎么会知道我在这儿? -你妈打电话告诉我的
-How'd you know I was here? -Your mom called me.
这就是她?
So is this her?
不,这是替代品
No,this is a .
我们的还在商店里
Ours is at the shop.
天哪,我希望她有我的头脑
God,I hope she has my brains.
抱歉,让你自己承担这一切
I'm sorry you had to do this by yourself.
我不是自己一个,我有大夫,护士和善心人士
I wasn't by myself. I had a doctor,a nurse and a helper guy.
-知道谁赢吗? -尼克斯胜十分,他们真烂
-So did you see who won the game? -The Knicks by 10. They suck.
他们还不算是太烂
They're not so bad.
拜托,拜托
Come on. Come on.
-你做的太辛苦了. -你应该更努力或者其他什么
-You're doing it too hard. -You have to do it hard or else
可恶,可恶
Damn it. Damn it.
可恶…都是你的错
Damn it,damn it. This is all your fault.
这本来是我今生最快乐的日子
This should be the greatest day of my life.
我儿子即将出世,我应该在那儿的
My son is being born,and I should be in there.
而不是被困在这儿
Instead,I'm stuck in a closet with you.
我和你一样期待已久
I have been waiting for this as much as you.
不,相信我没人像我如此期待
No one's been waiting for this as much as I have.
你知道什么最搞笑吗?
You know what's funny?
讽刺的是你们将带着宝宝回家 我剩下什么?
You go home with the baby. Where does that leave me?
你是他父亲
You're his father.
我是谁?这世上有父亲节,母亲节
Who am l? There's Father's Day. There's Mother's Day.
却没有女同志节
There's no Lesbian Lover Day.
每天都是女同志节
Every day is Lesbian Lover Day.
这真精彩
This is so great.
愿意解释这句话吗?
Do you wanna explain that?
因为我小时候我爸离开
I mean,when I was growing up,my dad left...
我妈过世,我继父入狱
...and my mother died and my stepfather went to jail.
我根本得不到父母的爱
I barely had enough pieces to make one whole parent.
如今他有如此爱他的三个父母
And here's this baby who has three whole parents...
甚至为谁给他的爱最多而吵架
...who fight over who gets to love it the most...
而且他根本还未出世
...and it's not even born yet.
他真是全天下最幸福的宝宝
It's just the luckiest baby in the whole world.
抱歉,你们正在吵架
I'm sorry. You were fighting.
他们在哪儿?
Where are they?
-他们会来的? -他们不会错过的
-They'll be here. -They wouldn't miss this.
放轻松.才开了九公分,宝宝没那么快出来
Relax. You're only at 9 centimeters,and the baby's at zero station.
你吓到我了
You are really frightening me.
谁愿意帮我吗?她想掏出我的心脏
Somebody wanna help me? Trying to rip out my heart.
这下可好,有人看见乳头吗?
That's great. Anybody seen a nipple?
十公分,开始用力
Ten centimeters. Here we go.
-开始用力 -但是他们还没过来
-Time to start pushing. -But they're not here yet.
-我无法叫宝宝等他们来 -哦,上帝
-I can't tell the baby to wait. -Oh,God.
-通气口开了 -我是班
-Okay,got the vent open. -Hi,I'm Ben.
我是医院工人班
I'm hospital worker Ben.
班前来抢救了
It's Ben to the rescue.
班,准备好没?脚给我
Ben,you ready? Give me your foot.
数到三,班.1,2,3
On three,Ben. One,two,three.
来吧,班.就是这样,班
Come on,Ben. That's it,Ben.
你看见什么?
What do you see?
我看见黑暗的通气孔
I see what appears to be a dark vent.
等等
Wait.
真的是黑暗的通气孔
Yes,it is,in fact,a dark vent.
菲比,门开了
Pheebs,it's open. It's open.
等等,你们忘了脚
Wait. You forgot your legs.
-用力,用力 -我们来了,我们来了
-Push. Push. -We're here. We're here.
你们上哪儿去了
Where have you been?
说来话长
Long story.
卡萝,我要你不断用力 抱歉,我能用这个吗？
I need you to keep pushing. I need Excuse me,can I have this?
这里人太多了,而且待会儿又会多一个
There's too many people here. There's about to be one more.
所以不是前任丈夫和女同志伴侣者请出去
So if you're not an ex-husband or lesbian life partner,out you go.
-再见了…? -祝你好运.伙计
-Bye-bye. -Good luck,you guys.
必须要卡萝的女同志伴侣才行吗?
Do you have to be Carol's lesbian life partner?
出去
Out.
他的头露出来了
Here he comes.
让我看看…我看到了
Let me see. I've gotta see.
是头…
A head.
好大,卡萝,你是怎么办到的?
It's huge. How are you doing this?
你真是一点忙都帮不上
You're not helping.
你做得很好…
You're doing great.
-喂！ -哦,对不起
-Hello? -Oh,sorry.
你看见什么?你看见什么?
What do you see? What do you see?
我看到头,手臂出来了,看看这些小手指
We got a head. We got arms. Oh,look at the little fingers.
看,是手指,肚子
A chest and a stomach...
是男的,百分百男孩
...and it's a boy,definitely a boy.
腿,膝盖和脚
Legs,knees and feet.
他出来了
He's here.
他是个人
He's a person.
-看. -他看起来像谁?
-Look. -What does he look like?
像我叔叔艾德,被吉露牌的果冻包着
IKind of like my Uncle Ed,covered in Jell-O.
真的?
Really?
各位,他好漂亮
You guys,he's beautiful.
谢了,菲比
Thanks,Pheebs.
不准大吼,我们仍需要为他取个名字
No shouting,but we still need a name for this little guy.
-班如何? -我喜欢班
-How about Ben? -I like Ben.
班
Ben.
这名字不错,你们之前怎没提过这名字?
Ben's good. How come you never mentioned Ben before?
刚想出来的
We just cooked it up.
这就是我们不在时做的事
That's what we were off doing.
-我们能进来吗? -当然,请进
-Can we come in? -Yeah,come on.
我知道,我知道
I know. I know.
各位,向你们介绍一个人
Everybody,there's someone I'd like you to meet.
-他叫班. -嗨,班
-This is Ben. -Hi,Ben.
班,这是大家
Ben,this is everybody.
苏珊,他看起来像你
Susan,he looks just like you.
谢谢
Thanks.
天啊,没想到我们之中有人生宝宝了
I can't believe one of us actually has one of these.
我知道,我也是其中之一
I know. I still am one of these.
我能吗?
Can l?
好,头,你必须…
Okay,the head. You gotta....
班,我是你姑姑莫妮卡,没错
I'm your Aunt Monica. Yes,I am.
我就是你姑姑莫妮卡
I'm your Aunt Monica.
我将永远准备口香糖给你（美国父母不允许孩子多吃糖）
I will always have gum.
班…
Ben...
我要你知道有时我会不在
... I want you to know that there may be some times when...
像这样
... I may not be around like this.
我会回来
But I'll still always come back...
像这样
...Iike this.
有时我会离开更久
And sometimes,I may be away longer...
像这样
...Iike this.
我仍会回来
But I'll still always come back...
像这样
...Iike this.
有时我要你到三垒的位置,我会这样
And sometimes,I'll want you to steal third and I'll go like this:
他太神奇了
He is so amazing.
对,我知道,你看他
Yeah,I know. Look at him.
没反应,我想这名字不适合他
Nothing. I don't think that's his name.
看,他闭上眼睛了
Look,he's closing his eyes.
看,他张开眼睛了
Look,he's opening his eyes.
他不常这样吧?
He doesn't do much,does he?
不，他经常这样
Nope,this is pretty much it.
你们想喝咖啡吗?
You guys wanna get some coffee?
待会儿见
I'll see you guys later.
看,他又闭上眼睛了
He's closing his eyes again.